<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://cofea.readthedocs.io</id>
  <title>Blog</title>
  <updated>2021-01-20T19:48:39.147218+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://cofea.readthedocs.io"/>
  <link href="https://cofea.readthedocs.io/reference/blog/atom.xml"/>
  <generator uri="https://ablog.readthedocs.org" version="0.10.12">ABlog</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>https://cofea.readthedocs.io/reference/blog/2020-12-10.html</id>
    <title>Engineering simulations without limits. The origin of CoFEA Initiative ☕</title>
    <updated>2020-12-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Slawomir Polanski</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Although the numerical simulations have been available for engineers for more than 50 years, I don’t feel they are as popular as they deserve to be. Some software vendors want to ‘democratize’ the simulation by simplifying its usage. It might be a way to make simulations more popular, but I am not sure if the term ‘democratization’ is the right word. As far as I remember the economic status should not matter in a real democracy, but it does matter in the proposed type of democratization. It is very likely that more engineers would use simulations if they weren’t that expensive. There is also another flip side of this approach… How much the developers can simplify the usage of software before it becomes a black-box solution? I bet some people would even argue that any software which is not open-source is essentially a black-box, but I am not that strict with the rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must admit I have been thinking for some time on how to introduce computer simulations in more companies. It seems to be a highly complex problem with a non-unique solution. That is why I feel like any contribution will help, so I would like to present my own initiative. Since the beginning of November, I have been working on my new after-hours project which I called CoFEA (Collaboration + Finite Element Analysis). CoFEA is an initiative that aims to bring open-source simulation software closer to the engineering industry problems. The goals of this initiative is to:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;script type="text/x-thebe-config"&gt;
    {
        requestKernel: true,
        binderOptions: {
            repo: "binder-examples/jupyter-stacks-datascience",
            ref: "master",
        },
        codeMirrorConfig: {
            theme: "abcdef",
            mode: "python"
        },
        kernelOptions: {
            kernelName: "python3",
            path: "./reference"
        },
        predefinedOutput: true
    }
    &lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;script&gt;kernelName = 'python3'&lt;/script&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://cofea.readthedocs.io/reference/blog/2020-12-10.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2020-12-10T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
